<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project 3</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Project 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loss of copy number variant in RGS10 and GRK5 in human patient to potentially cause Horner Syndrome through increased neuronal inflammation</title>
      <link>/project/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project4/</guid>
      <description>SummaryHorner Syndrome (HS) is a subtle, non-lethal disorder that is caused by lesions such as tumors or inflammation to the oculosympathetic pathway (Martin, 2018). Symptoms of HS include droopy eyelids, constriction of the pupil, and displacement of the eye in the eye socket (Walton&amp;amp; Buono, 2003). There have been no genes identified that cause this disorder nor is the mode of inheritance well known. However, this paper seeks to identify the potential genetic causation of Horner Syndrome through analysis of DECIPHER patients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetics of FMR1 on Fragile X Syndrome</title>
      <link>/project/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project5/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetics is the study of heritable changes in phenotype without changing DNA nucleotide sequence (Gibney &amp;amp; Nolan, 2010). It has become a popular field of research where scientists try to better understand the impact of epigenetics and gene expression on human diseases. Epigenetic modifications can be found on both the DNA and histones. Histones are positively charged proteins that assist in chromatin folding, which can actively express or repress gene expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposed Gli Enhancer Target Gene *Smoc1* Involved In Limb Development By Hedgehog Signal Using GREAT.</title>
      <link>/project/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project3/</guid>
      <description>SummaryThis paper identifies potential target genes regulated by Hedgehog (HH) signaling during limb development. It is known that Gli3 binding can repress or activate Sonic Hedgehog (Shh) target genes. Active Gli enhancers were identified using H3K27ac enrichment and was obtained through ChIP-seq. This reveals regions of DNA where there was increased Gli3 binding and H3K27ac modification (Lex et al., 2020). An intersection was made of the two enrichment files and processed by GREAT to find genes regulated by HH signaling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Happiness Score and Alcohol Consumption per Country</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>The two datasets I chose are about the happiness index of countries (2019) and the average alcohol servings of countries. I got this dataset from kaggle and the world happiness report. The happiness_index dataset includes countries, their rank in happiness, the happiness score, GPD per capita, social support, healthy life expectancy, freedom to make life choices, generosity, and perceptions of corruption. These variables were calculated by surverying citizens of each country on each statistic and using a complex formula to calculate the score of happiness index to get the rank of each country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Medical Insurance Data</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Datasetlibrary(tidyverse)insurance &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;https://drive.google.com/uc?export=download&amp;amp;id=1wYKOxnrDBJlyefVwvyUIzAmGn_VMpE9M&amp;quot;)glimpse(insurance)## Rows: 1,338## Columns: 7## $ age &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 19, 18, 28, 33, 32, 31, 46, 37, 37, 60, 25, 62, 23, 56, 27...## $ sex &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;quot;female&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;male&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;male&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;male&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;male&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;female&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;femal...## $ bmi &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt; 27.900, 33.770, 33.000, 22.705, 28.880, 25.740, 33.440, 27...## $ children &amp;lt;int&amp;gt; 0, 1, 3, 0, 0, 0, 1, 3, 2, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 0, 1, 1, 0, 0, 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python vs R</title>
      <link>/post/2020/12/05/python-vs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/12/05/python-vs-r/</guid>
      <description>Learning about data wrangling was tough enough this semester, but throw in some python and now my head is really spinning. During the last few lectures, the most surprising thing was that you can actually code python in RStudio! This can be done by creating python code chunks.
First ensure the “reticulate” package has been installed and now let’s try some python coding! Fingers crossed! Hopefully it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
Check out some of my research projects below:
 UCSC Genome Browser: Identifying Potential Genes Regulated by Sonic Hedgehog Signaling Involved in Limb Development
 Using DECIPHER Patient Genomic Information to Propose Causes of Genetic Disorders’
 Analysis of the Epigenetic Causations of Fragile X Syndrome and Potential Methods of Treatment</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
